现在我们正在编写规范和思考
Now that we're writing specifications and thinking
关于客户如何使用我们的方法，
about how clients will use our methods,
我们来谈谈如何处理特殊情况
let's talk about how to handle exceptional cases
在某种程度上，这是安全的，从错误和容易理解。
in a way that's safe from bugs and easy to understand.
记住一个方法的签名——它的名字，
So remember that a method's signature-- its name,
它的参数类型和返回类型--
its parameter types, and its return type--
都是其规范的核心部分。
are all a core part of its specification.
在Java和许多其他语言中的签名
And that signature in Java and in many other languages
也可以包含方法可能触发的异常。
can also include exceptions that the method might trigger.
所以你可能已经看到了一些例外
So you've already seen some exceptions probably
在Java编程或Python编程中
in your Java programming or in your Python programming
在那之前。
before that.
常见异常的几个例子
Couple of examples of common exceptions
数组索引超出了
are array index out of bounds which
当您尝试使用
you'll get when you try to index into an array using
超出有效范围的索引，
an index that's outside of its valid range,
或发生空指针异常
or null pointer exception which happens
当试图对空对象引用调用方法时。
when you try to call a method on a null object reference.
我们在这篇文章的前面讨论过这个问题。
We talked about that a little earlier in this reading.
这类异常--数组
These kinds of exceptions-- array
越界和空指针异常--
out of bounds and null pointer exceptions--
通常是代码中的错误。
are generally bugs in your code.
它们是你不希望发生的事情
They're things that you don't expect to happen
也不想发生。
and don't want to happen.
Java显示的信息，
The information displayed by Java,
抛出异常时显示的堆栈跟踪，
the stack trace that is shown when the exception is thrown,
可以帮助你找到并修复
can help you find and fix the bug that
导致错误的数组索引或使用空指针。
led to that wrong array index or to using that null pointer.
数组索引和空指针可能是最常见的异常
Array index and null pointer are probably most common exceptions
你会看到这种情况的。
you'll see of this kind.
其他的例子是算术异常，
Other examples are arithmetic exception,
当你除以0，更多的数字格式时
which can happen when you divide by zero, more number format
异常，当您试图解析一个实际上不是
exception, when you try to parse a string that is not actually
一个数字。
a number.
所以这些是典型的错误例子，
So those are typically examples of bugs,
但是有另一种使用异常的方法，
but there's another way that exceptions are used,
不仅仅是为了给错误发信号和帮助你找到它们，还有更多
not just for signaling bugs and helping you find them, but more
有意地，更多地作为你设计的一部分
intentionally, more as part of your design
帮助改进代码结构
to help improve the structure of your code
还有程序，让你的方法表明
and have procedures, have your methods signal that they
有特殊的结果。
have special results.
现在我们将对比特殊情况下使用异常
Now we're going to contrast using exceptions for special
与处理特殊结果的另一种常见方法相反的结果
results against another common way of handling special results
其实可以追溯到很多很多年前
that actually dates back many, many years ago to earlier
没有异常处理的编程语言，
programming languages that did not have exception handling,
通常是C，在C++的旧版本上。
typically C, on old versions of C++.
这种方法仍然存在，这里是你通常看到的。
And this approach persists and here's what you typically see.
所以一个方法返回一个int，然后得到一个特殊的值，
So a method returns an int and you get a special value,
就像消极的，当出了问题。
like negative one, when something has gone wrong.
或者当方法
Or you get a null reference when the method
应该返回一个对象而不是返回
is supposed to return an object instead of returning
一个普通的物体。
an ordinary object.
所以如果你谨慎使用这种方法是可以的，
So this approach is OK if you use it sparingly,
但在实践中并没有得到很好的应用
but it's not used very sparingly in practice
它有两个问题。
and it has two problems.
首先，它强制程序员
First of all, it forces the programmer
记住要检查返回值，
to remember to check that return value,
不幸的是，对于程序员来说
and unfortunately, it's very easy for the programmer
忘记做那件事。
to forget to do that.
例如，如果你打电话给find
So for example, if you're calling find
当它不能
and it's error behavior when it can't
找到你要找的东西
find the thing that you're looking
为了返回一个负数，程序员
for is to return a negative one, the programmer
可能只是想，哦，我有一个索引回来了。
may just think, oh, I got an index back.
我将继续使用这个索引。
I'm going to go ahead and use that index.
然后那个负数在程序中传播
And then that negative one is propagating through the program
也许在离他们实际所在地很远的地方
and maybe somewhere very far away from where they actually
称为find，它实际上会抛出一个超出界限的索引
called find, it will actually throw an index out of bounds
在那里。
there.
或者它可能永远不会抛出任何错误
Or it may never throw any error at all
只会产生一个错误的答案。
and simply produce a wrong answer.
所以我们以前也讨论过这个问题。
So we've talked about that problem before.
这就是快速失败的问题。
That's the failure to fail fast problem.
所以这是一个用特殊值作为方法的问题
So that's one problem with using special values as a way
发出异常情况的信号。
to signal unusual cases.
这是另一种方法。
Here's another way.
还有一个问题。
Here's another problem.
找到这种特殊的价值并不总是容易的。
It may not always be easy to find that special value.
所以假设我们有一本关于生日的书
So suppose we have, for example, a book of the birthdates
所以这是一节课
of your friends and so this is a class
它应该代表那本书。
and it's supposed to represent that book.
你给它一个你朋友的名字。
You give it the name of one of your friends.
它应该会返回那个人的生日。
It's supposed to return that person's birthdate.
这个本地日期类是Java的一部分
This local date class is part of the Java
API，那就把它当成约会吧，
API, so just think of it as being a date,
但它是个物体。
but it's an object.
如果生日那天我们该怎么办
Well what should we do if the birthday
书上没有名字的条目？
book doesn't have an entry for the person whose name is given?
好吧，我们可以回个特别的日期
Well, we could return some special date
我们不会把它当作真正的约会对象。
that we're not going to use as a real date.
事实上，糟糕的程序员
In fact, bad programmers have been
做了很长一段时间。
doing that for a long time.
在上个世纪，在20世纪，
In the last century, in the 20th century,
像这样的约会回来并不少见
it was not uncommon to return a date like this
因为很明显1960年没有程序
since it was obvious that no program written in 1960
仍将在1999年运行。
would still be running in 1999.
所以这是一个非常安全的事情，作为一个不约会回来。
So this was a perfectly safe thing to return as not a date.
结果发现那些人错了
Turns out those people were wrong
当我们翻车的时候
and this caused a big problem when we rolled over
从1999年到2000年。
from 1999 to 2000.
这里有一个更好的方法。
Here's a better approach.
这个查找功能，当它不能
This look up function, when it can't
查找此人的姓名会引发异常。
find the person's name can throw an exception.
这是故意的例外。
It's an intentional exception.
在很多情况下，我们都希望能得到它。
It's one that we're expecting to get in many cases.
这对我们来说并不罕见
It's not going to be unusual for us
试着把名字传给这本生日书
to try to pass a name to this birthday book
发现他们不在里面。
and find that they're not in there.
所以这个签名，方法声明
So this signature, the method declares
除了返回本地日期，
that in addition to returning local date,
一种可能的方法
one of the possible ways that it can return
就是抛出这个异常。
is by throwing this exception.
这里有一个关于
And here's sort of a sketch of how
它会看到这个函数的内部。
it would look inside the body of that function.
但从来电者的角度来看，
But from the caller's point of view,
他们首先假设，
what they do is they first assume,
一切都会好起来的
well, everything's going to go fine
我们会在书中找到艾莉莎
and we're going to find Alyssa in the book
它将返回一个本地日期
and it's going to return a local date
我们可以把它赋给生日并使用它。
and we can assign that to birthdate and use it.
但在某些情况下，我们可能找不到艾莉莎
But in some cases, we may not find Alyssa, in which case
我们有一个单独的catch子句
we have this separate catch clause that
处理没有找到艾莉莎生日的案子。
deals with the case where Alyssa's birthday is not found.
所以现在不需要任何特别的价值。
So there's no need now for any special value.
这段代码周围没有空值。
We don't have any nulls floating around this code.
我们没有任何可能传播的负面影响。
We don't have any negative ones that might propagate.
我们没有任何无效日期
We don't have any invalid dates that might someday actually
有效。
be valid.
编译器实际上在帮助
And the compiler is actually helping
我们检查所有这些案子。
us check that we're handling all of these cases.
我们现在谈谈这个。
Let's talk about that now.
所以我们看到了两个不同的目的
So we've seen two different purposes
例外情况——特别的结果，比如在生日那天
for exceptions-- special results, like in the birthday
我们刚看到的书，还有窃听器，
book we just saw, and bug detection,
类似于空指针异常。
like null pointer exceptions.
一般来说，您需要使用选中的异常
As a general rule, you'll want to use checked exceptions
向信号发送特殊结果和未经检查的异常
to signal special results and unchecked exceptions to signal
漏洞。
bugs.
我们将讨论什么是检查和未检查
We're going to talk about what checked and unchecked
现在是例外。
exceptions are right now.
这是一般规则，但在下一节中
This is a general rule, but in the next section
在这篇文章中，我们将对它进行一些改进，因为
of this reading, we're going to refine this a bit because it's
在某些方面会有点过于严格。
going to be a little bit too strict for some purposes.
而且Java库确实违反了这个一般规则。
And the Java library does violate this general rule.
我们来谈谈原因。
We'll talk about why.
但首先，什么是检查异常和未检查
But first, what are checked exceptions and unchecked
例外情况？
exceptions?
所以checked异常称为checked
So checked exceptions are called checked
因为编译器会在编译时检查它们。
because the compiler will check them at compile time.
也就是说，它将确保如果一个方法可能抛出
That is, it will make sure that if a method might throw
一个选中的异常——如果它的主体中有
a checked exception-- if it has in its body
诸如此类的事情——而且没有发现例外
something like this-- and NotFoundException
是已检查的异常之一，
is one of the checked exceptions,
然后编译器将确保我们声明
then the compiler is going to ensure that we declared
在查找的方法签名中引发NotFoundException
throws NotFoundException in the method signature of the lookup
方法。
method.
因此，NotFoundException是我们将其设为checked异常
So NotFoundException is we would make it a checked exception
这就是签名中有抛出子句的原因。
and that's why the signature has that throws clause in it.
如果我们这里没有这个，那么
And if we didn't have this here, then
编译器会给我们一个错误并告诉我们
the compiler would give us an error and tell us
我们得把它放在那里。
we have to put that there.
检查的第二部分是如果一个方法调用
Second part of the checking is that if a method calls
另一个可能抛出checked异常的方法——所以
another method that might throw checked exception-- so
这里，这里的代码，这里的客户端代码
here, this code here, this client code that
正在调用birthdays.lookup刚刚声明
is calling birthdays.lookup just declared that it
引发NotFoundException。
throws a NotFoundException.
编译器将确保
The compiler's going to ensure that we
在这段代码中以某种方式处理可能的异常。
deal with that possible exception somehow in this code.
有两种方法可以解决这个问题。
And there's two ways to deal with it.
要么我们就在这里抓住它，
Either we're catching it right here,
这就是代码现在所做的。
and that's what this code is doing right now.
或者另一种方法是声明异常
Or the other way to do it is to declare the exception
在它自己的签名里。
in its own signature.
所以包含此代码的方法
So the method that contains this code here
可能会引发NotFoundException本身
might throw NotFoundException itself
如果它没有抓住它。
if it wasn't catching it.
那是因为例外的方式
And that's because the way exceptions
工作是如果他们不是真的被抓在这里，
work is if they're not actually caught here,
然后他们就会跳出这个方法
then they will jump out of this method
传播到调用方。
and propagate up to the caller.
所以检查异常，我们让编译器确保
So checked exceptions, we have the compiler making sure
在某种程度上，我们正在处理这个例外。
that at some point we are dealing with that exception.
这非常有用，因为它可以确保
This is really useful because it ensures
我们期望发生的例外--
that exceptions that we expect to occur--
换句话说，这些特殊的结果
in other words, these special results that
是该方法的有效可能结果，
are a valid possible result of the method,
即使没有可能发生的错误
even in the absence of bugs that could happen-- they
将确保这些都得到处理。
will ensure that those are handled.
另一类例外
Now the other category of exception
是未经检查的异常。
are unchecked exceptions.
我们用这些信号来通知虫子，然后
And we use these to signal bugs, and we
不必在整个链条上申报
don't have to declare them all the way up the chain
因为我们不希望它们在正确的程序中发生。
because we don't expect them to happen in a correct program.
我们不希望调用链上的每个方法都有
We don't want every method up that call chain to have
声明它可能抛出与
to declare that it might throw all the kinds of bug related
可能发生的异常，如索引越界、空
exceptions that can happen, like index out of bounds, null
指针异常、合法参数、断言失败。
pointer exceptions, legal arguments, assertion failures.
任何一种都有可能发生在虫子的情况下。
Any one of those could happen in the case of a bug.
所以我们想让他们传播
And so we actually want them to propagate up
尽可能的合理，然后抓住他们并报告
as far as is reasonable and then catch them and report them
给程序员。
to the programmer.
所以对于未检查的异常，编译器
So for an unchecked exception, the compiler
不会检查尝试捕获。
will not check for a try catch.
它不需要抛出声明。
It won't require a throws declaration.
你仍然可以写一个抛出声明
You can still write a throws declaration
在未检查异常的方法签名上，
on your method signature for unchecked exceptions,
但这一点也不好笑。
but this has no effect at bit funny.
我们不建议这样做，有些编译器实际上
We don't recommend doing it and some compilers will actually
警告你。
warn you about it.
现在当你抛出一个异常，一个异常
Now when you throw an exception, an exception
可能有与之相关的消息
may have a message associated with them
写一点详细的信息是个好主意
and it's a good idea to write a bit of a detailed message
所以程序的用户
there so that the user of the program
明白发生了什么。
understands what's going on.
所以我们说——我们把
So we've said-- we've made the distinction between checked
未经检查。
and unchecked.
这在Java中是如何表示的？
How is that actually represented inside Java?
如何判断是否有例外
How do we say whether an exception
应该检查还是不检查？
should be checked or unchecked?
好吧，这是通过说哪门课来完成的--
Well it's done by saying which class--
哪种异常类--您的异常是
which kind of exception class-- your exception is
会延伸的。
going to extend.
这里是Java异常的类层次结构。
And here is the class hierarchy of Java exceptions.
所以在顶部，投掷物是可以投掷的物体
So at the top, throwables are objects that can be thrown
会被抓住的。
and can be caught.
有两种可抛。
And there are two kinds of throwable.
一个是例外，比如一个类，
One is an exception, such as a class,
这是我们用于检查异常的普通类。
that is the normal class that we use for checked exceptions.
错误是未经检查的异常，
And errors are unchecked exceptions,
但它们应该留给编译器使用
but they should be reserved for the compiler
在运行时系统中。
in the runtime system.
所以错误属于Java，程序员不应该
So error belongs to Java and programmers should not
子类错误。
subclass error.
然后运行时异常是超级类
And then runtime exception is the super class
未经检查的异常。
of unchecked exceptions.
所以我们区分
So the way that we distinguish between a checked
一个未经检查的异常
and an unchecked exception, the way
我们创建checked和unchecked异常是
that we create checked and unchecked exceptions is
如果我们想要检查异常，我们
if we want a checked exception, we're
将扩展异常。
going to extend exception.
如果我们想要一个未经检查的异常，
If we want an unchecked exception,
我们将扩展运行时异常。
we're going to extend runtime exception.